Curriculum Vitae

Jacob Halsey. Bristol, UK

Email: jacob@jhalsey.com

Website: https://www.jhalsey.com/

LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/jacob-halsey/

GitHub: https://github.com/jacob-pro

Personal Statement

I am currently a software engineer working for Oracle OCI (Oracle Cloud Infrastructure). I studied BSc Computer Science at the University of Bristol, and also have previous experience developing commercial iOS apps. I have good knowledge of computer systems and networks and I'm very enthusiastic about working with modern languages such as Rust that can ensure memory and concurrency safety without compromising performance.

Education

Undergraduate

University of Bristol: 2018 - 2021 BSc Computer Science (Results Pending)

A Level

Churston Grammar School: 2015 – 2017 Greenway Road, Brixham, TQ5 0LN

Computer Science: A*
Mathematics: A*

Further Mathematics: A

Economics: A Physics (AS): A

Westlands School: 2013 – 2015 Westlands Lane, Torquay, TQ1 3PE

BTEC Level 3 Diploma in IT: Distinction* Distinction*

GCSE

Brixham College: 2010 - 2015

Higher Ranscombe Road, Brixham, TQ5 9HF 9 GCSEs – Including four A* and four A grades

Experience

Software Engineer - Oracle: 2021 - Present

Working as part of the API Gateway team at Oracle Cloud Infrastructure.

Software Development Internship – Oracle: Summer 2019

I developed the backend for an internal tool used for auditing cloud resources, with a REST and WebSockets API developed in Java and deployed using Docker. I worked on performance metrics at the data plane of the API Gateway cloud service using Lua, and implemented scheduled business metrics at the control plane of the API Gateway service, along with a Grafana dashboard, used by management to monitor deployments and feature usage. I also worked on a feature to scale Gateways to support higher throughput.

Software Developer - Createanet: 2017 - 2018

Prior to starting university, I worked at Createanet for a year primarily as an iOS developer; I developed 6 iOS apps mainly using Objective-C (and also some Swift). One of these apps was a social media platform, others were for photo and video sharing, electronic forms, and video conferencing.

I also developed REST APIs and administration websites to manage the apps using PHP and MySQL.

Part-Time – IT Support, Brixham College: 2011 – 2015

Whilst I was at Brixham College I had a part time job with the IT department. This mainly involved working with Microsoft products such as Windows Server, Active Directory, Exchange Server, and Hyper-V. I was responsible for setting up the automated deployment of operating systems and software, first using WDS and later SCCM, for around 500 PCs. I also configured and maintained the Remote Desktop services infrastructure for staff, students, and thin PCs.

I also maintain a list of projects I have worked on at my website, showing the software languages and frameworks that I am familiar with.

Certifications

CCNA R&S: 2016 - 2019

I passed the Cisco Certified Network Associate Routing and Switching exams entirely self-taught. Topics included IPv4/6, TCP/UDP, Ethernet (VLANs, STP, security), static and dynamic routing.

Full UK Drivers License: 2018 - present